<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1" ?><wwwjob id="11e5ad3aP5BH" method="Update"><ref_no>00020927</ref_no>
<division>001</division>
<position>Client Accountant</position>
<start_date>TBA</start_date>
<location>Douglas</location>
<salary>TBA</salary>
<job_type type="P">Permanent</job_type>
<consultant_email>registrations@hamblin.co.im</consultant_email>
<consultant_phone>01624 620022</consultant_phone>
<consultant_fax>01624 677057</consultant_fax>
<consultant_name>Registrations</consultant_name>
<consultant_code>REGISTER</consultant_code>
<category number="1"><job_category group="24" code="PERMNNT">24PERMNNT</job_category>
</category><category number="2"><job_category group="10" code="FULLTIME">10FULLTIME</job_category>
</category><category number="3"><job_category group="A " code="FINSERVS">A FINSERVS</job_category>
</category><category number="4"></category><category number="5"></category><category number="6"></category><category number="7"></category><category number="8"></category><category number="9"></category><category number="10"></category><long_description>Duties include:
&#183; Work with all members of the office and with the other offices within the Group with the aim of ensuring that all designated clients&#39; accounts are dealt with in a timely and professional manner. To support the line manager where necessary and cover work due to absence. To carry out other duties as required by the line manager including review of financial statements prepared by other team members
&#183; Be aware of all ongoing and outstanding work within your area of responsibility. To ensure the correct prioritisation of work, to ensure that all deadlines are adhered to and that clients are properly informed when this is not possible
&#183; Be responsible for financial and accounting requirements for client entities including bookkeeping, statutory accounts, payroll, VAT and taxation. Dealing with internal and external queries in person, in writing and by telephone in a professional and courteous manner
&#183; Monitor and remind clients of deadlines for the filing of Tax, VAT Returns and Sales Lists and the payment of the relevant taxes in order to ensure that penalties are not unnecessarily incurred 
&#183; Keeping up to date with client accounting and VAT procedures, reporting and accountancy standards and changes in legislation including VAT changes across the EU
&#183; Prepare files for accounts and VAT and ensure the good order of such files and to open new files when old files become full and cumbersome
&#183; Ensure that accounting and VAT records are kept up to date for all companies on the ViewPoint Administrator system
&#183; Ensure that the correct amounts of time, fixed fees and disbursements in respect of client accounting work are entered onto the ViewPoint systems for later invoicing
&#183; Ensure that all company policies and procedures are understood and followed correctly including anti money laundering provisions

Skills and experience required:
&#183; Part qualified and ideally working towards a recognised and relevant professional qualification (ACCA/ACA/CIMA)
&#183; Experience in a fiduciary environment  
&#183; Ability to maintain bookkeeping records and prepare statutory financial statements
&#183; Knowledge of UK GAAP
&#183; Awareness of the changes in UK financial reporting (FRS 102)
&#183; Good working knowledge of Microsoft Word and Excel
&#183; Knowledge of Viewpoint, QuickBooks and IRIS would be an advantage
	
</long_description>
<date_published date="2017-11-01" time="14:54">01 Nov 2017 at 14:54</date_published>
<published_by>ANGELA</published_by>
<spare_1></spare_1>
<spare_2></spare_2>
<spare_3></spare_3>
</wwwjob>